[PEARL]
Hey!
When did you get back?
I can't miss this
for the world.
I got accepted in the
scholarship, Sir Han.
I know.
Pearl…
[KOREAN]
I love you.
Sir Han...
I love you, too.
- [ARIEL] Han Bin oppa!
- [KARA] Nice to see you!
Hug, hug, hug, hug!
[CAROL CRIES]
[JAO]
Kara?
Surprise visit?
You're so dramatic.
Of course I came to see you, too.
[KARA CHUCKLES]
Thank you so much
for the offer.
I'll let you know my
decision by Friday.
[PURE COAST OFFICER]
Thank you, Caitlyn.
We're looking forward to working with
you here in Denmark and wherever...
[CAROL]
You know that...
I support you, right?
Wherever you may go.
Are you happy?
Jao, I'm leaving Siargao.
Kara, you're leaving the island?
I always say I'll
go with the flow.
But this time...
I'll decide where
the flow takes me.
Will this make you happy?
[JAO] If you ever
decide to come back,
just find me
where you left me.
[FIRE CRACKLING]
Jao, I'm sorry.
I love you, Kara.
I love you, too, Jao.
What now?
[JAO]
Just like before…
We’ll just go with the flow.
And let the wave take us.
[ALON BY JL]
[KARA SNIFFS]
[KARA CRIES SOFTLY]
[WOMAN]
Here.
Thank you.
Sorry.
Just cry it out.
Tears of joy or pain?
[KARA CHUCKLES]
[KARA BREATHES DEEPLY]
Both.
Boat.
[KARA CHUCKLES]
[WOMAN]
What?
Nothing.
It’s okay.
I know the feeling.
Did you get hit by
the Siargao Curse?
It wasn't a curse.
It was a blessing.
[KARA LAUGHS]
Thank you for this.
- [WOMAN] Want more?
- Yes, please.
[PA SYSTEM] Final boarding call for
flight 2R 990 bound for Clark, Pampanga.
[WOMAN] You can have it.
- [KARA] Thank you.
[PA SYSTEM] Final boarding call for
flight 2R 990 bound for Clark, Pampanga.
[KARA CRIES]
[KARA BREATHES DEEPLY]
[WOMAN]
See you!
[KARA EXHALES]
[KARA BREATHES DEEPLY]
[USAD BY CUATRO]
[KOREAN]
Wow, you’re totally crazy!
The curse is real!
Yes!
[LAUGHING]
[KARA] Long time no see!
When did you get back?
- Hi, Kara!
- [KARA] It's aligned, right?
Ariel, give Kara a hand.
You’re smiling like this!
- So this is smiling?
- Yes!
- Does he smell good?
- [KARA LAUGHS]
Like baby powder?
Doesn’t he always look like
he smells like baby powder?
- Right?
- [KARA LAUGHS]
- Thanks, Carol.
- I love you.
[KARA]
Super thank you.
You deserve it, okay?
Okay.
Enough drama.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[JAO]
Wait! Wait!
You're going to need some fuel
because things are getting intense here.
Hug, hug, hug, hug!
[CAROL CRIES]
Kara, Jao.
Kara, Jao...
[SIARGAONON]
Karajaw!
Like the Siargaonon
term for “super”!
Wow! Wonderful!
Right?
Look.
There’s pancit in the sky!
It wasn’t Siargao.
And you weren’t there.
You’re not extending your stay?
- No, don’t tempt me!
- [KARA LAUGHS]
Ruth, this is Jao.
Jao, Ruth.
We hope you'll support
Pure Coast's goal...
Team Mangroves forever!
[CROWD CHEERING]
- [JAO] Use both hands. There you go.
- [KARA] There.
- [ARIEL] There you go.
- [JAO] Push it down first.
[KARA CRIES]
[KARA BREATHES HEAVILY]
[KARA SNIFFS]
[KARA BREATHES DEEPLY]
[FLIGHT ATTENDANT]
Okay.
[JAO VOICEOVER] A lot of people
wonder if the Siargao Curse is real,
or if people simply stay
because they love it here.
It's not hard to fall
in love with Siargao.
We have everything here.
Pristine nature.
Friendship and community.
[LAUGHING]
[JAO VOICEOVER]
Family.
Okay, come on.
More, more photos.
- Come on, Jao, it’s time to eat!
- Am I okay here?
- We’ve taken a lot already.
- [JAO] Yes, Carol. Just sit right there.
You, Mr. Han…
switch sides.
[HAN BIN]
Oh, okay.
So many pictures.
We've been at this forever!
- [JAO] Okay, ready.
- Okay, let's go!
- Let’s eat!
- Let's move closer.
- Closer, closer, closer!
- [ARIEL] This better be the last one!
- [HAN BIN] Closer? Closer?
- Closer. Ready. One…
We’re closer!
[JAO]
One… two…
Okay.
- [HAN BIN] Okay!
- [ARIEL] That’s the last one, okay?
[ARIEL] Mom, let's eat.
Where's the grilled fish?
But, wait, look at this.
Something’s weird with your photo, guys.
[CAROL] Didn’t we bring
the grilled fish earlier?
- [ARIEL] It’s Princess...
- [CAROL] Isn't that...
- [ARIEL] Mom! It’s Princess Pearl!
- [CAROL SCREAMS EXCITEDLY]
- [HAN BIN SCREAMS EXCITEDLY]
- [ARIEL] Pearl’s here!
[ARIEL] Hey! Hey, Pearl,
why did you hug him first?
- [ARIEL] He got to hug you before we did!
- I really missed you!
[ARIEL]
We’re your family, remember?
- [PEARL] Ariel!
[CAROL] You didn't tell us!
[CAROL]
Who picked you up?
[ARIEL]
When did you get here?
- [CAROL] Who picked you up at the airport?
- [PEARL] Tantan did!
[ARIEL]
It was you? Tantan!
- [ARIEL] You didn't even tell us!
- [PEARL] Jao!
Welcome back.
[ARIEL]
Hey, you're so special!
The first one to be hugged.
[ARIEL]
Hey.
- [PEARL] I missed you, too.
- [ARIEL] Hey, what about the laptop I asked you to buy?
- [HAN BIN] I miss you so much.
- [ARIEL] Hey, I asked you to buy it for me.
[CAROL]
It's so pretty!
[JAO VOICEOVER]
There’s so much in this island.
But some say love
is the ultimate curse.
But every curse has a cure.
A cure that only time can bring.
[WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
[JAO VOICEOVER] Two years ago,
I learned my greatest lesson in life
when I came home to Siargao.
I learned that love is the
opposite of possession.
Love...
is freedom.
It's wishing the
person you love well,
even though they chose a
journey different from yours.
[NOAH]
Caitlyn!
Is that it?
[NOAH]
Yes.
“A writ of preliminary injunction
is hereby issued, ordering
Northern Summit Mining Corporation
to immediately cease and desist
from all mining and related
activities within the subject areas.
Effective immediately.”
We did it!
[NOAH] Perfect timing,
right when you got back to Manila.
Looks like they were just waiting for
you before handing over the resolution.
[KARA] We should
let the elders know.
The two community leaders
are on their way here.
They want to
personally thank you.
Since you’re the one who got this
started before you left for Denmark.
I'm just happy they'll finally be
able to protect their ancestral land.
- The world is healing!
- [KARA LAUGHS]
Sir Noah,
I'm heading to the airport.
Where are you going?
They're being dispatched
today to their new assignment.
To Siargao.
Have you been?
If love was a place,
it would be Siargao.
[BRUSHING TEETH]
[SWISHING WATER]
[HAN BIN CLEARS THROAT]
Pearl, you're so pretty.
Pearl, you're so beautiful.
Sir Han!
Mom.
Dad.
Uh...
The house I'm building
here is almost finished.
I'm excited to come
home here every Sunday.
I've just been so busy in GL.
There's so much going on.
Mom, if only you could see...
the developments
happening there now.
It's so different now from
the General Luna I grew up in.
Mom, Dad...
Thank you.
Thank you for everything...
you've taught me.
Thank you for inspiring me.
Because of that,
I finally found
where I belong.
Thank you.
[JAO SNIFFS]
Mom, Dad,
I hope...
you're proud of me.
And...
I hope you're
proud of your son.
[EGAY]
Uncle Jao!
Oh! Egay!
[JAO] You've been
the one bringing these?
You're such a good kid.
Let me see those grades.
Wow. 98?
That’s your average?
That's really high!
I'm in the top 10.
Very good!
Up here.
Let's go.
What do you want?
We have to celebrate.
Since you got
good grades.
Let's eat at GL Pizza.
GL Pizza? What else?
How about we get a burger with that?
Come on,
what else do you want?
- [JAO] Besides pizza.
- Chicharon.
Chicharon?
(Deep-fried pork rinds)
What a weird combo.
Bye, Mom! Bye, Dad!
Love you!
[JAO VOICEOVER]
Love is a curse.
And they say,
Siargao has a curse.
[SIARGAONON]
Siargao is beautiful!
[JAO VOICEOVER]
But if you're lucky,
and you find the
right person for you
here on the island,
and the timing is right...
the Siargao Curse…
can turn into...
Siargao Magic.
[JAO VOICEOVER]
And only then you will realize...
that love is not a curse.
Love is more than just magic.
Because love is a place.
A place you can
always come home to.
How are you?
[SIARGAONON]
Absolutely wonderful.